[
    {
        "question": "What is India’s total external debt in 2023, as per the World Bank International Debt Report?",
        "options": [
            "$610.67 billion",
            "$635.84 billion",
            "$646.79 billion",
            "$655.74 billion",
            "$675.95 billion"
        ],
        "answer": "$646.79 billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mutual fund company launched the Quant Fund, an open-ended equity scheme based on a quant-based investing approach?",
        "options": [
            "HDFC Mutual Fund",
            "ICICI Prudential Mutual Fund",
            "SBI Mutual Fund",
            "Kotak Mahindra Mutual Fund",
            "Axis Mutual Fund"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which general insurance company has Mahindra Finance signed a strategic corporate agency agreement?",
        "options": [
            "ICICI Lombard General Insurance",
            "Magma HDI General Insurance",
            "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance",
            "HDFC ERGO General Insurance",
            "Reliance General Insurance"
        ],
        "answer": "Magma HDI General Insurance"
    },
    {
        "question": "As of October 31, 2024, how many accounts have been opened under the Mahila Samman Savings Certificate Scheme?",
        "options": [
            "30.50 lakh",
            "35.20 lakh",
            "40.30 lakh",
            "43.30 lakh",
            "45.70 lakh"
        ],
        "answer": "43.30 lakh"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the growth rate of bank credit to NBFCs in October 2024 compared to the same period last year?",
        "options": [
            "10.2%",
            "12.5%",
            "6.4%",
            "8.0%",
            "18.3%"
        ],
        "answer": "6.4%"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization has Razorpay collaborated with to enhance the security of India's digital payments ecosystem?",
        "options": [
            "Reserve Bank of India",
            "Ministry of Home Affairs",
            "Indian Cyber Crime Coordination Centre",
            "Both b and c",
            "National Payments Corporation of India"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the nation-wide drive launched by State Bank of India (SBI)?",
        "options": [
            "To promote digital banking",
            "To raise awareness about inoperative account activation",
            "To offer new banking services",
            "To encourage saving habits",
            "To introduce new loan schemes"
        ],
        "answer": "To raise awareness about inoperative account activation"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much has India contributed to the BRICS New Development Bank (NDB), and how much has been loaned for externally aided projects in areas like transportation?",
        "options": [
            "$1 billion; $3,528 million",
            "$1.5 billion; $4,074 million",
            "$2 billion; $4,867 million",
            "$2.5 billion; $5,575 million",
            "$3 billion; $6,500 million"
        ],
        "answer": "$2 billion; $4,867 million"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company has had the restrictions imposed by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) lifted, led by Sachin Bansal?",
        "options": [
            "Paytm",
            "Navi Finserv",
            "Lendingkart",
            "Bajaj Finserv",
            "Finbox"
        ],
        "answer": "Navi Finserv"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two companies have ended their co-branded credit cards partnership?",
        "options": [
            "ICICI Bank and HDFC Bank",
            "RBL Bank and Bajaj Finance",
            "Axis Bank and Kotak Mahindra Bank",
            "SBI and HDFC Bank",
            "IDFC Bank and Yes Bank"
        ],
        "answer": "RBL Bank and Bajaj Finance"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much does Bank of India (BoI) plan to raise through the issuance of infrastructure bonds?",
        "options": [
            "₹3,000 crore",
            "₹4,000 crore",
            "₹6,000 crore",
            "₹7,000 crore",
            "₹5,000 crore"
        ],
        "answer": "₹5,000 crore"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main goal of the partnership between Mahindra Finance and Magma HDI General Insurance?",
        "options": [
            "To introduce new insurance products",
            "To expand financial access for emerging India",
            "To enhance digital payment solutions",
            "To offer co-branded credit cards",
            "To promote investment in agriculture"
        ],
        "answer": "To expand financial access for emerging India"
    },
    {
        "question": "What significant milestone has SBI Card recently achieved?",
        "options": [
            "Surpassing 15 million credit cards in circulation",
            "Surpassing 20 million credit cards in circulation",
            "Entering the international credit card market",
            "Reaching 10 million active users",
            "Launching its 100th credit card variant"
        ],
        "answer": "Surpassing 20 million credit cards in circulation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What initiative has the Reserve Bank of India (RBI), led by Governor Shaktikanta Das, announced to enhance public communication and financial literacy?",
        "options": [
            "Launch of a new mobile app",
            "Launch of a podcast series",
            "Organizing national seminars",
            "Launch of an online financial literacy course",
            "Introduction of financial literacy campaigns in schools"
        ],
        "answer": "Launch of a podcast series"
    },
    {
        "question": "What new facility has the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) enabled for Small Finance Banks?",
        "options": [
            "Offering loans without collateral",
            "Offering insurance services",
            "Enabling foreign currency exchange",
            "Providing micro-investment options",
            "Offering pre-sanctioned credit via UPI"
        ],
        "answer": "Offering pre-sanctioned credit via UPI"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is set to introduce the Banking Laws (Amendment) Bill, 2024 in the Lok Sabha?",
        "options": [
            "Narendra Modi",
            "Nirmala Sitharaman",
            "Amit Shah",
            "Shaktikanta Das",
            "Pankaj Chaudhary"
        ],
        "answer": "Nirmala Sitharaman"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary age group targeted by HDFC SKY's newly launched Youth Plan?",
        "options": [
            "16 to 22 years",
            "18 to 25 years",
            "20 to 30 years",
            "21 to 28 years",
            "18 to 30 years"
        ],
        "answer": "18 to 25 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new CEO of DBS Bank India, effective March 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Surojit Shome",
            "Rajat Verma",
            "Piyush Gupta",
            "Gautam Jain",
            "Vedant Mahajan"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the reason for the RBI imposing penalties on Manappuram Finance and IndusInd Bank?",
        "options": [
            "Failure to maintain minimum capital adequacy ratios",
            "Inadequate reporting of non-performing assets (NPAs)",
            "Violation of foreign exchange management laws",
            "Non-compliance with regulations, including verification of customer PAN",
            "Both 1 & 2"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following payment systems saw a growth in transaction volume in November compared to October 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Unified Payments Interface (UPI)",
            "Immediate Payment Service (IMPS)",
            "FASTag",
            "Aadhaar Enabled Payment System (AePS)",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization approved a grant of 25.45 million US dollars to the Solomon Islands for the development of sustainable water supply and sanitation services?",
        "options": [
            "Asian Development Bank (ADB)",
            "World Bank",
            "International Monetary Fund (IMF)",
            "New Development Bank",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Asian Development Bank (ADB)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What mandate has the RBI issued regarding RTGS and NEFT transactions by April 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Enable free cross-border fund transfers.",
            "Implement a beneficiary account name lookup feature for free.",
            "Increase the transaction limit for RTGS and NEFT transfers.",
            "Launch a new digital payment platform for RTGS and NEFT.",
            "Both 3 & 4"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the RBI's 15-day credit score update rule:\n1. Lenders are mandated to update credit bureau records every 15 days.\n2. The rule enhances borrowers' credit visibility by promptly reflecting repayments and missed payments.\n3. This system aims to replace the yearly update system, effective from January 1, 2025.\nWhich of the following options is correct?",
        "options": [
            "Only 1",
            "Only 1 and 2",
            "Only 1 and 3",
            "Only 2 and 3",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Only 1 and 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RBI's stricter regulatory oversight for Housing Finance Companies (HFCs) includes reducing the ceiling on public deposits HFCs can borrow to ________ of their net-owned funds.",
        "options": [
            "2 times",
            "2.5 times",
            "1 time",
            "1.5 times",
            "3 times"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the RBI's beneficiary account name look-up facility for RTGS and NEFT expected to be implemented?",
        "options": [
            "January 1, 2025",
            "April 1, 2025",
            "March 31, 2025",
            "July 1, 2025",
            "December 31, 2024"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RBI's Report on Trend and Progress of Banking in India 2023-24 highlighted that the Gross Non-Performing Assets (GNPA) ratio declined to ________, the lowest in 13 years, by March 2024.",
        "options": [
            "3.3%",
            "3.0%",
            "2.7%",
            "2.0%",
            "1.5%"
        ],
        "answer": "2.7%"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of CheQ's newly launched India's first AI-powered tool for credit card management?",
        "options": [
            "CreditEase",
            "CardAssist",
            "PayM",
            "Wisor",
            "None of the abocve"
        ],
        "answer": "Wisor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian company partnered with ESAF Small Finance Bank to offer vehicle financing solutions?",
        "options": [
            "Tata Motors",
            "Maruti Suzuki",
            "Ashok Leyland",
            "Mahindra & Mahindra",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements based on the RBI report released in January 2025:\n1. Credit cards almost doubled by Dec 2024, compared to 2019.\n2. Digital payments surged 94x in volume and 3.5x in value since 2013.\n3. UPI rise almost quadrupled, from 21% (2019) to 83% (2024).\nWhich of the above statements is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "Only 1 & 2",
            "Only 2 and 3",
            "Only 1 and 3",
            "All of the above",
            "Only 1"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much loan did the World Bank approve for Amaravati's Integrated Urban Development Program?",
        "options": [
            "$500 million",
            "$600 million",
            "$800 million",
            "$900 million",
            "$1000 million"
        ],
        "answer": "$800 million"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which UN organization has recognized six environmental leaders with the 2024 Champions of the Earth award for their efforts in tackling land degradation, drought, and desertification?",
        "options": [
            "UN Environment Program (UNEP)",
            "United Nations Development Program (UNDP)",
            "United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO)",
            "United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC)",
            "WWF"
        ],
        "answer": "UN Environment Program (UNEP)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization launched the Tiara Credit Card for women?",
        "options": [
            "State Bank of India",
            "BOBCARD Limited",
            "HDFC Bank",
            "ICICI Bank",
            "PNB"
        ],
        "answer": "BOBCARD Limited"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actor featured in the new brand campaign of Canara HSBC Life Insurance?",
        "options": [
            "Akshay Kumar",
            "Ranveer Singh",
            "Shah Rukh Khan",
            "Varun Sharma",
            "Ranbir Kapoor"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much money did NaBFID raise through 15-year bonds at a 7.25% cut-off rate?",
        "options": [
            "Rs 7,000 crore",
            "Rs 3,000 crore",
            "Rs 5,000 crore",
            "Rs 15,000 crore",
            "Rs 10,000 crore"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 5,000 crore"
    }
]